舰长，我们已经到达指定地点
Captain, we've reached the designated position
可以扫描编码指令带了
for scanning the coded directive tape.
很好
Good.
我们都猜对了
We've both guessed right.
“星际舰队与克林贡帝国的协商濒临破裂
"Negotiations with the Klingon Empire on the verge of breaking down.
指挥部准备进行一次突袭”
Starfleet Command anticipates a surprise attack."
我们的任务是“前往奥伽尼亚
We are to "proceed to Organia
并且采取一切必要措施
and take whatever steps are necessary
阻止克林贡人将其占为基地”
to prevent the Klingons from using it as a base."
战略上可行
Strategically sound.
奥伽尼亚是争议区的唯一一个M级行星
Organia is the only Class-M planet in the disputed area.
对双方来说都是一块战略要地
Ideally located for use by either side.
告诉我奥伽尼亚的基本信息，史波克
Organia's description, Mr. Spock?
那里栖息着类人生物
Inhabited by humanoids.
一支非常爱好和平且友好的种族
A very peaceful, friendly people.
生活方式还非常原始
Living on a primitive level.
没有什么进步
Little of intrinsic value.
大概处在里彻特文明量表的D-级
Approximately class D-minus on Richter's scale of cultures.
又一个亚美尼亚，比利时
Another Armenia, Belgium.
你说什么，长官？
Sir?
软弱的无辜者
The weak innocents
似乎总会因为生活在侵略路线上而被卷入其中
who always seem to be located on the natural invasion routes.
舰长，自动偏导护盾突然开动了
Captain, the automatic deflector screen just popped on.
- 有东西正在接近 - 是什么，苏鲁？
- Body approaching. - Configuration, Mr. Sulu?
相位炮组，锁定目标，反击
Phaser banks, lock on. Return fire.
保持攻势
Maintain firing rate.
开启全裂解模式
One hundred percent dispersal pattern.
我们击中目标了，目标被破坏了
We hit him, captain. He's hurt.
向大副报告受损情况
Damage control, report to the first officer.
舰长，侦测不到敌方星舰
Captain, the other ship doesn't register.
只剩下漂浮的残骸了
Only drifting debris.
- 我们击毁它了 - 所有人员保持警戒
- We got him. - All hands, maintain general alert.
维持作战状态
Hold battle stations.
回报损伤情况，史波克
Damage report, Mr. Spock.
损伤轻微，舰长，我们很幸运
Minor, captain. We were most fortunate.
10和11甲板层被炸损
Blast damage in Decks 10 and 11.
反物质防护罩有轻微凹陷
Minor buckling in the antimatter pods.
- 没有重大伤亡 - 继续侦测，苏鲁
- Casualties are light. - Maintain surveillance, Mr. Sulu.
侦测不到信号，舰长
No contact, captain.
敌舰已被完全击毁
He blew up, all right.
我们正在谋划一场突袭
Well, we've been anticipating an attack.
我想我们刚才经历的就正是一场突袭
I'd say what we've just experienced very nearly qualifies.
是的，那看来像是一次充满敌意的举动
Yes, it would seem to be an unfriendly act.
舰长，星际舰队司令部传来信息了
Automatic all-points relay from Starfleet Command, captain.
是一号指令
Code one.
好吧，终于来了，战争
Well, there it is. War.
我们不想要战争，但我们不得不打
We didn't want it, but we've got it.
我很好奇为什么你们人类经常会陷入
Curious how often you humans manage to obtain
你们不想要的战争
that which you do not want.
不论如何，我们有一项任务：
War or not, we've still got a job to do:
阻止克林贡人入驻奥伽尼亚
Denying Organia to the Klingons.
经过刚才那一役，这恐怕没那么简单了
With the outbreak of hostilities, that might not be easy.
- 前往奥伽尼亚 - 遵命，长官
- Lay in a course for Organia. - Aye, aye, sir.
和奥伽尼亚人协商需要不少时间，舰长
Negotiating with the Organians will be time-consuming, captain.
而时间正是我们所缺的
And time is the one thing we will have the least of.
我们无法通过简单的谈话就解决这事，史波克
Well, we won't get it by talking about it, Mr. Spock.
扳机已被扣动
The trigger's been pulled.
我们必须要在子弹射出去之前赶到那里
We've got to get there before the hammer falls.
七级曲速
Ahead warp factor 7.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命和新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
TLF荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：Nick
校对：Micezhang
第一季第二十六集
慈悲的使命
舰长日志，星历3198.4
Captain's log, stardate 3198.4.
我们已到达奥伽尼亚，正在其卫星轨道航行
We have reached Organia and established standard orbit.
这个区域没有发现敌对行为
No signs of hostile activities in this area.
舰长
Captain.
XY-75847单位在其侦测区域发现了一支克林贡舰队
Unit XY-75847 report a fleet of Klingon ships in their sector, sir.
- 什么方向？ - 无法确定，长官
- What bearing? - Unable to ascertain, sir.
苏鲁，让相位炮操作人员就位
Mr. Sulu, have the phaser crews stand by their positions.
把偏导护盾开至最大强度
Full power deflector screens.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
我和史波克要进行登陆，你来指挥舰队
Mr. Spock and I are going down to the planet's surface. You're in command.
你要对进取号负责，不是对我们俩负责，明白吗？
Your responsibility is to the Enterprise, not to us. Is that clear?
是的，长官
Perfectly, sir.
有一支克林贡舰队正在这个象限
A Klingon fleet is in this quadrant.
奥伽尼亚是他们的目标
We know that Organia will be a target.
如果他们出现了——
If they should emerge--
- 我们会对付他们的，长官 - 你要评估形势
- We'll handle them, sir. - You will evaluate the situation.
如果他们整支舰队都出现了，你们要撤退
If there is a fleet of them, you'll get out of here, Mr. Sulu.
- 但是，舰长—— - 没有但是
- But, captain-- - No buts.
你们要撤到安全的地方，向上头报告，不许单独作战
You'll get to safety and alert the fleet. You will not attack alone.
我和史波克会没事的
Mr. Spock and I will be all right.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
我们去会会奥伽尼亚人吧
Let's you and I pay the Organians a visit.
难道他们每天都会看到有人传送下来吗？
You'd think they had people beaming down every day.
他们似乎习以为常，真是奇怪
Yes. Curious lack of interest.
舰长，看到远处的废墟了吗，挺大的
Notice the ruins in the distance, captain. Quite large.
- 看到了，可能是座要塞，也可能是座城堡 - 不论是什么
- Yes. A fortress, perhaps. A castle. - Whatever it is,
这都与我们所接收到的
it would seem to be inconsistent with the reports
关于这个文明的报告内容不符
we've been given on this culture.
欢迎
Welcome.
这是来接待我们的吗？
Reception committee?
看来是
It seems so.
你们是我们的客人
You are our visitors.
欢迎，欢迎
Welcome, welcome.
我是艾尔波恩
I am Ayelborne.
我是联邦星舰进取号的詹姆士·T·寇克舰长
I am Captain James T. Kirk of the starship Enterprise,
代表星际联邦
representing the United Federation of Planets.
这是我的大副，史波克
This is my first officer, Mr. Spock.
欢迎你，我的朋友
You're most welcome, my friend.
我想和你们的当权者谈谈
I would like to speak to someone in authority.
我们这里没有什么当权者
We don't have anybody in authority.
但我是长者议会的主席，或许你可以和我谈谈
But I am the chairman of the Council of Elders. Perhaps I would do.
你的人民现正面临一个很大的危机
You people are in great danger.
我们能到什么地方谈谈吗？
Is there someplace we can go and talk?
是的，议事大厅就在附近，请
Yes, our council chambers are nearby. Please.
舰长
Captain.
如果你不介意，我想在村里走走
If you don't mind, I should like to wander about the village
做一些调查
and make some studies.
当然，请随便
Of course, my friend. Our village is yours.
舰长？
Captain?
先生们，我的政府告知我
Gentlemen, my government has informed me
克林贡人正打算要对你们的星球做出行动
that the Klingons are expected to move against your planet
将其变为他们的作战基地
with the objective of making it a base of operation
以对抗联邦
against the Federation.
坦白地讲，我的任务就是要阻止这一切的发生
My mission, frankly, is to keep them from doing it.
照舰长你所说，我们似乎有自由可以选择和你
What you are saying, captain, is that we seem to have a choice
或是和你的敌人进行谈判
between dealing with you or your enemies.
不是的，先生
No, sir.
如果和联邦形成统一战线，你才有自由
With the Federation, you have a choice.
但若接受克林贡的统治，就不是这样了
You have none with the Klingons.
克林贡人是一个接受军事独裁统治的民族
The Klingons are a military dictatorship.
战争是他们的生活方式
War is their way of life.
在克林贡人统治下的生活将会变得非常不愉快
Life under the Klingon rule would be very unpleasant.
我们可以向你们提供保护
We offer you protection.
我们对你们的无私奉献表示感谢，舰长
We thank you for your altruistic offer, captain,
但我们真的不需要你们的保护
but we really do not need your protection.
我们是一个简朴的民族，舰长
We are a simple people, captain.
我们没有别人想要的东西
We have nothing that anybody could want.
你们所居住的星球，其地理位置具有战略意义
You have this planet and its strategic location.
我可以保证，如果你们不采取措施保护它
I assure you that if you don't take action to prevent it,
克林贡人绝对会在日出时刻对你们采取行动
the Klingons will move against you just as surely as your sun rises.
我们会帮助你们构建国防，建设设施
We will help you build defences, build facilities.
我们没有什么国防，我们也不需要
We have no defences, captain. Nor are any needed.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我亲眼目睹过克林贡人对其他星球的所作所为
I have seen what the Klingons do to planets like yours.
它们被组织成巨大的奴隶劳动集中营
They are organised into vast slave-labour camps.
你们将失去自由，以及所有财产
No freedoms whatsoever. Your goods will be confiscated.
他们会掳掠、杀害人质，推翻领导人
Hostages taken, killed. Your leaders confined.
你们如果生活在一个法制星球上，生活会好很多
You'd be far better off on a penal planet. Infinitely better off.
舰长，我们能看出你的担忧是诚挚的，我们很感动
Captain, we see that your concern is genuine. We are moved.
但我们要向你重申，我们并没有面临危险
But again, we assure you that we are in absolutely no danger.
如果有人面临危险，那是你，而我们对此感到担忧
If anybody is in danger, you are. And that concerns us greatly.
如果你能尽快回到星舰上，情况会好很多
It would be better if you return to your ship as soon as possible.
你一直坚持没有危险
You keep insisting that there's no danger.
而我一直在警告你，你能告诉我——
I keep assuring you that there is. Would you mind telling me--?
这是我们的生活方式，舰长
It is our way of life, captain.
而那将会是你们最先失去的
That's the first thing that would be lost.
对不起，先生们
Excuse me, gentlemen.
我是一名军人，不是外交官
I'm a soldier, not a diplomat.
我只懂得说实话
I can only tell you the truth.
如果你不介意，我们想讨论一下
If you will excuse us, captain, we will discuss your kind offer.
当然
Yes, certainly.
舰长，我们之前收到的关于这星球的
Captain, our information on these people and their culture
情报有误
was not correct.
这个原始社会并没有在向工业化发展
This is not a primitive society making progress toward mechanisation.
而是完全处于停滞状态
They are totally stagnant.
没有任何进步的痕迹
There is no evidence of any progress
从三录仪能探测到的最远年限起就是这样
as far back as my tricorder can register.
- 那不太可能 - 但事实就是如此
- That doesn't seem likely. - Nevertheless, it is true.
在数万年以来
For tens of thousands of years,
就一直没有进步
there has been absolutely no advancement.
他们的居住环境没有明显变化
No significant change in their physical environment.
这是个典型的易被征服的文明
This is a laboratory specimen of an arrested culture.
谢谢你，史波克，这些信息或许会有用
Thank you, Mr. Spock. That might be useful.
我们讨论过了，舰长
We have discussed your offer, captain.
但我们仍然坚持我们的看法，我们没有面临危险
And our opinion is unchanged. We are in no danger.
我们感谢你们所愿意提供的帮助
We thank you for your kind offer of assistance,
但我们还是不能接受
although we must decline it.
我们强烈建议你们
And we strongly recommend that you leave Organia
在陷入困境之前离开奥伽尼亚
before you yourselves are endangered.
先生们，我希望你们能再考虑一下
Gentlemen, I must get you to reconsider.
我们能为你们带来很大的帮助
We can be of immense help to you.
除了军事支援
In addition to military aid,
我们可以向你们派送专家和技术人员
we can send you specialists, technicians.
教你们如何用同样的土地
We can show you how to feed a thousand people
生产1000倍的粮食，我们还可以帮你们建设学校
where one was fed before. We can help you build schools.
给年轻人教授最新的科学技术技能
Educate the young in the latest technological and scientific skills.
你们几乎没有公共设施
Your public facilities are almost nonexistent.
我们可以帮助你们改造世界
We can help you remake your world.
消灭疾病，饥饿，苦楚
End disease, hunger, hardship.
而我们需要的只是你们的同意
All we ask in return is that you let us help you. Now.
舰长，我想你并不了解我们
Captain, I can see that you do not understand us.
- 或许—— - 不好意思，先生
- Perhaps-- - Excuse me, sir.
我是寇克
Kirk here.
舰长，一大群克林贡星舰出现了
Captain, a large number of Klingon vessels have just arrived.
- 他们正在向我们开火 - 确认无误吗？
- They're opening fire. - Positive identification?
是的，长官，我打开了护盾，不能传送你们上来
Yes, sir. My screens are up. I can't drop them to beam you aboard.
苏鲁，执行命令
Mr. Sulu, follow your orders.
撤退，和司令部取得联系
Get out of here. Contact the fleet.
等你们有把握时再回来，呼叫完毕
Return if the odds are more equal. Kirk out.
先生们，你们坚持认为没有危险——
Gentlemen, you kept insisting that there was no danger--
是的，舰长，没有危险
That is correct, captain. There is no danger.
艾尔波恩，有八支星舰
Ayelborne, eight space vehicles
进入了我们的卫星轨道
have assumed orbit around our planet.
他们正在启动物质传送装置
They are activating their material transmission units.
我知道了，谢谢，特里非恩
Thank you, Trefayne.
他说的是真的吗？
Can you verify that?
我不知道，但那听起来很符合逻辑
Negative, captain, but it seems a logical development.
舰长，既然你已经走不了了
Captain, since it is too late for you to escape,
或许我们应该来保护你了
perhaps we should do something about protecting you.
如果你们刚才听进了我的话…
If you had listened to me...
我们必须确保你们不受伤害
We must be sure that you are not harmed.
艾尔波恩，有好几百人出现在了城堡附近
Ayelborne, several hundred men have appeared near the citadel.
他们带了很多武器
They bring many weapons.
他怎么知道？
How does he know that?
特里非恩的直觉很准
Our friend Trefayne is really quite intuitive.
你们可以相信他所说的话
You can rest assured that what he says is absolutely correct.
所以…
So...
…我们被困在这了
...we're stranded here.
被克林贡侵略军队困住了
In the middle of a Klingon occupation army.
是的
So it would seem.
情况有点糟糕
Not a very pleasant prospect.
你说话倒是挺擅长轻描淡写的，史波克
You have a gift for understatement, Mr. Spock.
真的挺糟糕的
It's not a very pleasant prospect at all.
舰长日志，星历3201.7
Captain's log, stardate 3201.7.
我和史波克被困在了奥伽尼亚
Mr. Spock and I are trapped on the planet Organia,
而它正处于被克林贡帝国
which is in the process of being occupied
征服的过程中
by the forces of the Klingon Empire.
奥伽尼亚人给我们提供了本地人服装
The Organians have provided us with native clothing
希望我们能被当作是本地人
in the hopes that we may be taken for Organians.
舰长，我们的相位枪不见了
Captain, our phasers are gone.
- 是你拿了吗？ - 是的，舰长，我拿了
- Did you take them? - Yes, captain, I took them.
我希望你能还给我们
I must ask you to return them.
抱歉，舰长，我不能还给你们
I'm sorry, captain. I cannot do that.
如果你们拥有了武装，你们或许会使用暴力
Were you armed, you might be tempted to use violence,
而我们不允许那种事发生
and that we cannot permit.
你，舰长，要伪装成一个奥伽尼亚人
You, captain, will pass as an Organian.
而史波克先生…
And Mr. Spock...
史波克先生就有点麻烦了
Mr. Spock presents a problem.
他的外表不像奥伽尼亚人
He does not look like an Organian.
或许可以伪装成瓦肯商人
A Vulcan trader, perhaps.
做药草生意的商人，对克林贡人没有威胁
A dealer in kevas and trillium. Harmless to the Klingons.
他们知道瓦肯星附属于联邦
They know that Vulcan is a member of the Federation.
瓦肯商人并不少见，舰长
Vulcan merchants are not uncommon, captain.
这个方法可行
It is a practical approach.
那你们呢？
What about the rest of you?
我们就一如既往
We shall continue as before.
没什么好怕的
We have nothing to fear.
但你们还有一些事不明白
You have a lot to learn, sir.
而如果我是对的，你们的学习过程会很不愉快
And if I know the Klingons, you'll be learning it the hard way.
这里是执政委员会吗？
This is the ruling council?
我是艾尔波恩，委员会的临时主席
I am Ayelborne, temporary head of the council.
欢迎你
I bid you welcome.
是的
No doubt you do.
我是柯尔，奥伽尼亚的军事统领
I am Kor, military governor of Organia.
你是谁？
Who are you?
他是巴罗纳，我们的一个公民领导
He is Baroner, one of our leading citizens.
他不会说话吗？
And he has no tongue?
我会说话
I have a tongue.
很好
Good.
我们会教你学会怎么说话
You will be taught how to use it.
- 你怎么不笑？ - 什么？
- Where is your smile? - My what?
他们那种愚蠢的笑容，你怎么没有
The stupid, idiotic smile everyone else seems to be wearing.
瓦肯人
A Vulcan.
你会说话吗？
Do you also have a tongue?
我叫史波克
I am Spock.
草药商人
A dealer in kevas and trillium.
你看来不像是个商人，带走这个人
You do not look like a storekeeper. Take this man.
瓦肯隶属于联邦，他可能是个间谍
Vulcans are members of the Federation. He may be a spy.
他不是间谍
He's no spy.
噢
Well.
我们这是不是有只出头鸟？
Have we a ram among the sheep?
你不同意让我们带走他吗？
You object to us taking him?
他什么都没做过
He's done nothing. Nothing at all.
对于奥伽尼亚人来说，你这样已经算是在造反了
Coming from an Organian, yours is practically an act of rebellion.
很好
Very good.
你们欢迎我
So you welcome me.
那你欢迎我吗？
Do you also welcome me?
你已经在这了，我改变不了什么
You're here. There's nothing I can do about it.
很好，你很真诚
Good, honest hatred.
让我印象深刻
Very refreshing.
但不论如何，你欢不欢迎都没用了
However, it makes no difference whether you welcome me or not.
我来了，而且我会留下
I am here, and I will stay.
你现在是克林贡帝国的一枚棋子
You are now subjects of the Klingon Empire.
我们有很多法律法规
You will find there are many rules and regulations.
它们将被通告
They will be posted.
只要违反了这些条规就会被处以死刑
Violation of the smallest of them will be punished by death.
我们会遵守你们的条令的，长官
We shall obey your regulations, commander.
- 你不同意吗，巴罗纳？ - 你需要我同意吗？
- You disapprove, Baroner? - Do you need my approval?
我不要别的
I need your obedience.
只要你的服从
Nothing more.
你会服从我吗？
Will I have it?
看来我别无选择
You seem to be in command.
是的
Yes.
的确
I am.
我需要从你们之中挑选一个代表
I shall need a representative from among you.
作为统治者和平民间的桥梁
Liaison between the forces of the occupation and the civil population.
笑，笑，笑
Smile and smile.
我不信任喜欢笑的人
I don't trust men who smile too much.
你，巴罗纳，就你了
You, Baroner. You're the man.
我？我不想要这份差事
Me? I don't want the job.
我有问你想不想要吗？
Have I asked whether or not you want it?
我们克林贡人的残忍是有名的
We Klingons have a reputation for ruthlessness.
你会发现我们的名气并不是空穴来风
You will find that it is deserved.
如果有一个克林贡士兵被杀了…
Should one Klingon soldier be killed...
…我们会杀掉1000个奥伽尼亚人
...a thousand Organians will die.
你们要服从我的权威
I will have order.
明白吗？
Is that clear?
指挥官，我向你保证
Commander, I assure you,
我们的人民只想要和平
our people want nothing but peace.
我们不会给你惹麻烦的
We shall cause you no trouble.
我相信你们不会的
I am sure you will not.
把这个瓦肯人带去检查室
Take the Vulcan to the examination room.
你，给我过来
You. Come with me.
我会让你熟悉你的新工作
I will familiarize you with your new duties.
史波克呢？
What about Mr. Spock?
- 你很担心吗？ - 他是我的朋友
- You are concerned? - He is my friend.
你真不会交朋友
You have a poor choice of friends.
他要接受检查，如果他在撒谎，他会被处死
He will be examined. If he is lying, he will die.
如果他没撒谎…
If he is telling the truth...
…那恐怕他的生意要遭到些挫折了
...he will find that business has taken a turn for the worse.
把他押下去
Take him.
你不喜欢被推着吧
You do not like to be pushed.
很好
Very good.
我可能会和你合得来，巴罗纳
You may be a man I can deal with, Baroner.
跟我来
Come with me.
“从今天开始
"From this day on,
公共场合不允许三人以上的聚会
no public assemblages of more than three people.
所有的出版物都将在这里被清查
All publications to be cleared through this office.
社区管理将被建立
Neighbourhood controls will be established.
人质将会被选出”
Hostages selected."
这张单子列出了国家规定的不可违逆的条例
A somewhat lengthy list of crimes against the state.
你不满意吗？
You do not like them?
怎么样了？
Well?
他没说谎，指挥官
He is what he claims to be, commander.
他是个叫史波克的瓦肯商人
A Vulcanian merchant named Spock.
如今他最关心的是如何
His main concern seems to be
在我们的统治下做生意
how he would carry out his business under our occupation.
没别的了吗？
Nothing else?
没什么特别的了
The usual.
他对我们有一定的了解
A certain amount of apprehension regarding us.
他的思想非常清晰稳定
His mind is remarkably disciplined.
你确定吗？
You are sure?
我使用了第四档
I used force four,
那已经足以揭露所有伪装了
which is sufficient to break down any pretence.
很好，上尉
Very well, lieutenant.
你想试试我们的思维抽吸装置吗？
Would you like to try our little truth-finder?
我不知道那是什么
I don't understand it.
根据所使用的档数不同
It's a mind sifter. Or a mind ripper,
它可以用来筛选或者抽取思想
depending on how much force is used.
我们能获得一个人脑子里
We can record every thought.
所拥有的所有思想和知识
Every bit of knowledge in a man's mind.
当然了，如果要做到那种程度
Of course, when that much force is used,
那么这个人的思想就要被抽干了
the mind is emptied.
永远地变成一个植物人
Permanently, I'm afraid. What's left is more vegetable than human.
你为这种做法感到骄傲吗？
And you're proud of it?
这是一种工具，一种武器
It is a tool, a weapon.
或许有点过激，但很有效
Somewhat drastic, but very efficient.
你没事吧？
Are you sure you're all right?
没事，巴罗纳
Perfectly, Baroner.
但那经历还挺有意思的
But it was an interesting experience.
好吧，瓦肯人，你可以走了
All right, Vulcan, you may go.
但你是个敌国公民
But you are an enemy alien.
所以我们会一直监视你
You will be under our scrutiny at all times.
如果要我警告你的话…
If I have to warn you...
不需要了，指挥官
Not necessary, commander.
我明白了
I understand you very well.
回到你的议会去，巴罗纳
Return to your council, Baroner.
你将会在第一时间接收到
You will receive our official notifications
我们的官方通告
as soon as they are published.
而在此期间，维持好公民秩序
In the meantime, keep the people in order.
这是你的责任
It is your responsibility.
否则我就会被处死
Or I will be killed.
是的，说得对
That is exactly right.
你会被处死
You will be killed.
那个仪器看来也没他们想的那么厉害
That mind sifter can't be all the terror they think it is.
你不应该小看它，舰长
It should not be underestimated, captain.
它可以直接入侵思想
It reaches directly into the mind.
我们瓦肯人有一种精神——
We Vulcans have certain mental--
一些特质，可以给我的思想提供屏障
Certain disciplines which enable me to maintain a shield.
如果没有这些特质，就没有防护了
Without those disciplines, there would be no protection.
我会尽量远离它的
I'll try and avoid it.
让开，奥伽尼亚人
Out of the way, Organian.
对不起，先生，我们没注意到你
I'm sorry, sir. We did not notice you.
下次把眼睛给我睁大点，不然我就把它们缝起来
Next time keep your eyes open, or I'll shut them permanently.
舰长
Captain.
我强烈建议我们把精力
I strongly suggest we direct our energies
放在主要问题上：
toward the immediate problem:
完成我们的任务
Accomplishing our mission here.
你不会真的觉得我会揍他吧？
You didn't really think I was gonna beat his head in, did you?
- 我以为你会 - 是的，我真的会
- I thought you might. - You're right.
但正如你所说，我们还有任务
But as you say, we still have a job to do.
我们无法从奥伽尼亚人那里获取帮助
We'll receive no help from the Organians.
或许吧，但他们迟早会对克林贡人的
Maybe. But sooner or later, they're gonna start resenting
统治方式感到愤恨
how the Klingons run things.
如果我们能让他们相信他们可以反抗
If we could prove to them they could do something to strike back,
可以推翻克林贡人的政权的话
to keep the Klingons off balance.
口头劝说似乎没什么效果
Verbal persuasion seems to be ineffective.
或许我们需要更加直接的方法
Perhaps a more direct approach.
我正有此意
That's exactly what I had in mind.
史波克，柯尔的指挥部外面
Mr. Spock, did I or did I not see something
是不是有个类似军需库的地方？
that looked like a munitions dump outside of Kor's headquarters?
是的
You did.
我觉得我们今晚要开始做些简单直白的宣传工作了
I think it's time we did a little simple and plain communicating tonight.
你说的没错，舰长
A very meritorious idea, captain.
我们缺少工具
We're short of tools.
我相信克林贡人会有我们要的工具的
I'm certain the Klingons will provide whatever is necessary.
能和你共事真愉快，史波克
It's a pleasure doing business with you, Mr. Spock.
目前情况尚好
Okay so far.
音波手榴弹？
Sonic grenade?
- 有延迟爆破功能 - 很好
- With a delayed-action fuse. - Good.
这些箱子里有化学易爆品
These crates contain chemical explosives.
炸起来一定相当壮观
They should make a most satisfactory display.
6，5，4，3…
Six, five, four, three...
你说得没错，史波克
You were right, Mr. Spock.
的确很壮观
A most satisfactory display.
我们当然要炸了它
Of course we blew it up.
这势在必行
Deliberately.
但那是暴力
But that was violence.
我们是想证明，你们可以反抗
We did it to show you could fight back.
不一定只能一味服从
That you don't have to be sheep, you can be wolves.
要搞破坏吗
Terrible.
那太可怕了
To destroy.
历史上文明社会成功反抗独裁统治的例子
History is full of examples of civil populations
比比皆是
fighting back successfully against a military dictatorship.
也许我们无法消灭克林贡人，但可以囚禁他们
We may not be able to destroy the Klingons, but we can tie them up.
炸掉他们的设施，干扰他们的通讯设备
Blow up their installations. Disrupt their communications.
让他们放弃侵略奥伽尼亚
Make Organia useless to them.
我们的舰队一定会来的
Our fleet will eventually arrive.
在那之前，我们要进行斗争
In the meantime, the battle is ours.
我们会成功的
It can be a successful one.
舰长，我希望你不要再做这种事了
Captain, I implore you never to do such a thing again.
为什么？
Why?
你害怕有报应吗？
Are you afraid of retribution?
你们的个人自由难道就这么不值钱吗？
Does your personal freedom mean so little to you?
你太不了解我们了，舰长
How little you understand us, captain.
我所知道的你们
All I understand is that you don't have the backbone
都是些没种去保护自己所爱的人的懦夫
to stand up and fight and protect the ones you love.
我说的是勇气
I speak of courage, gentlemen.
难道勇气对你们来说什么都不是吗？
Does courage mean so little to you?
你说到勇气
You speak of courage.
但很显然，你不明白勇气…
Obviously, you do not know the difference between courage...
…和有勇无谋的区别
...and foolhardiness.
从来都是那些只有匹夫之勇的人会遭殃
Always it is the brave ones who die. The soldiers.
我希望你能继续享受你的美好生活
I hope you will continue to savour the sweetness of your life.
你让我反胃
You disgust me.
你想怎么处置他，指挥官？
What are you going to do with him, commander?
就像处置间谍和内鬼一样
What is always done with spies and saboteurs.
他将被处死…
He will be killed...
…但在那之前，我会让他好好体验下思维抽吸装置
...after he has had firsthand experience of our mind scanner.
指挥官，你没必要对他使用那台仪器
There's no need to use your machine on him, commander.
我可以告诉你他的名字
I can tell you his name.
他是詹姆士·T·寇克舰长
It is Captain James T. Kirk.
- 艾尔波恩 - 什么？
- Ayelborne. - What?
联邦星舰进取号的舰长
Captain of the USS Enterprise.
星舰指挥官
A starship commander.
还有副官？
And his first officer?
我本来以为会和你在战斗中相遇，但是…
I had hoped to meet you in battle, but...
因为某些原因，他认为必须解决你，指挥官
For some reason, he feels that he must destroy you, commander.
就像你想解决掉他一样
Just as you feel you must destroy him.
恐怕你的计划要落空了
That's going to be rather difficult now.
不是吗，舰长？
Isn't it, captain?
多么令人敬佩的民族
What an admirable people.
你们总是这么背叛自己的朋友吗？
Do you always betray your friends?
我不希望你伤害他
I didn't want you to harm him.
对不起，舰长
I'm sorry, captain.
这是为了你们好
It was for the best.
你们不会受到伤害的
No harm would come of it.
我已经不惧怕死亡
I'm used to the idea of dying.
但我不想为你们这样的人而死
But I have no desire to die for the likes of you.
我不怪你，舰长
I don't blame you, captain.
把这个瓦肯人关起来
Lock up the Vulcan.
把舰长押到我的办公室
Take the captain to my office.
我们来谈谈
We'll have a talk.
在我对他做出…
Before I do what...
…最后处决之前
...must be done.
- 要喝一杯吗，舰长？ - 不，谢谢
- You'll have a drink with me, captain? - No, thank you.
我向你保证，我没有下药
I assure you, it isn't drugged.
我们有思想抽吸装置，无需这种下三滥手段
With our mind scanner, we have no need for such crude methods.
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want from me?
哦，太多了
Oh, a very great deal.
但首先，我想和你谈谈
But first I want to talk.
只是谈谈
Just talk.
你觉得我会就坐在这里然后和我的敌人“谈谈”？
Do you think I'm gonna sit here and "just talk" with the enemy?
你会的
You'll talk.
要么就在这主动和我谈，要么我就要用那仪器了
Either here, now, voluntarily, or under our mind scanner.
事实上，舰长，我很欣赏
The fact is, captain, I have a great admiration
你们联邦星际舰队
for your Starfleet.
那是一个很好的工具
A remarkable instrument.
另外我也必须承认我对你的欣赏
And I must confess to a certain admiration for you.
我知道昨天是你炸毁了我们的补给
I know, of course, that it was you who destroyed our supplies last night.
是吗？
Something was destroyed?
希望都是些关键的东西
Nothing inconsequential, I hope.
不是的
Hardly.
它们的确对我们很重要，但可以被替代
They were quite important to us, but they can be replaced.
来自联邦的你们
You of the Federation,
和我们很像
you are much like us.
我们才不像你们
We're nothing like you.
我们有民主的体制
We're a democratic body.
舰长，我不是说我们在意识形态上相似
Come now, captain. I'm not referring to minor ideological differences.
我是说就本性而言
I mean that we are similar as a species.
我们现在所处的星球上生活着一群绵羊
Here we are, on a planet of sheep.
而我们是老虎
Two tigers.
捕食者，猎人，杀手
Predators. Hunters. Killers.
而正因为如此，我们才这么伟大
And it is precisely that which makes us great.
我们可以占领整个宇宙
And there is a universe to be taken.
指挥官，在这个广阔无垠的宇宙里
It's a very large universe, commander.
到处都有不喜欢克林贡帝国的人
Full of people who don't like the Klingons.
很好
Excellent.
那就要看看谁更强大了
Then it shall be a matter of testing each other's wills and power.
想要活命必须要做出努力
Survival must be earned, captain.
把你们舰队的位置告诉我
Tell me about the dispersal of your starfleet.
省点吧，我不会说的
Go climb a tree.
我可以用思维扫描器获取我要的信息
I can get what I want through our mind scanner,
但那样的话你可能要变成植物人了，舰长
but there would be very little of your mind left, captain.
我可不想看你变成那样
I have no desire to see you become a vegetable.
你的那个瓦肯人朋友…
This friend of yours, the Vulcan...
…似乎有能力抵抗我们的装置
...he seems to have the ability to block our scanner.
我会找到原因的
I think, perhaps, I will find out why.
我要对他进行解剖
I will have him dissected.
你的朋友会被杀掉，而你则会变成一个植物人
Your friend killed. You, a mental vegetable.
这可不妙哦，舰长
Not a pleasant prospect, captain.
除非你把我想知道的东西告诉我
But it lies ahead for you unless you tell me everything I want to know.
12个小时，舰长
Twelve hours, captain.
那点时间可不够，指挥官
It will take a lot longer than that, commander.
那是我给你的最长期限
Longer than that, I will not wait.
舰长，我对你心怀敬意，但是…
I respect you, captain, but...
…这是战争
...this is war.
而我们对胜利志在必得
A game we Klingons play to win.
把他押到牢房和他朋友待在一起
Take him to the cell with his friend.
看好他
And watch him closely.
没用的，吉姆，无处可逃
No use, Jim. No way out.
我们还剩多少时间？
How much of the 12 hours do we have left?
6小时43分钟
Six hours, 43 minutes.
但不知道那些克林贡人准不准时
If the Klingons are punctual.
我觉得他们会的
I think we can count on them being punctual.
炸掉那个军需库并不够
Blowing that munitions dump wasn't enough.
如果我们能从这出去，我们必须直接攻击柯尔
If we get out of here, we've got to carry the attack directly to Kor.
这些奥伽尼亚人…
These Organians...
他们好像不明白
They do not seem to understand.
- 太奇怪了 - 但是我们还是要执行我们的任务
- Most peculiar. - Nevertheless, our orders still stand.
我们要采取行动扰乱克林贡的统治
We've got to make some attempt to neutralise the Klingon occupation.
我们可能没有机会了，舰长
We may not get the chance, captain.
这些墙很厚
These walls are very thick.
而且大厅里每隔几尺就有士兵把守
And there are guards every few feet down the hall.
哦，你们在这呢，先生们
Oh, there you are, gentlemen.
我相信你们应该都没什么大碍吧
I trust you are in good health.
- 我们走吧 - 走？
- Shall we go? - Go?
是的，那些人准备对你们动粗
Yes, your captors plan to do violence to you.
我们不希望看到那种事发生
That we cannot permit.
我是来带你们走的
I came to take you away.
你背叛了我们
You turned us over to them.
现在还想让我们相信你？
You expect us to trust you now?
你觉得你还有选择吗，舰长？
Is there really a choice, captain?
我会向你提供安全保障
I offer you safety.
我们不能待在这，他们很快就会发现我们的
We can't stay here. This is the first place they'll look.
他们不会来这找的，舰长，相信我吧
They will not come here, captain. You may believe me.
你先是背叛了我们，现在又要帮我们逃脱
First you turn us in, then you get us out.
你到底是在干什么？难道克林贡人提供了赏金
What are you doing now? Waiting for the Klingons to post a reward
所以你想故意再抓我们一次？
so you can turn us in again and collect it?
你太不了解我们了，舰长
How little you understand us, captain.
那些守卫又是怎么回事
Nor do we understand what happened to the guards at the citadel.
别担心这些事了
Please do not concern yourself about them.
他们怎么了？
What happened to them?
你不用担心，他们很好，舰长
Why, nothing happened to them, captain.
他们没事
Nothing at all.
指挥官
Commander.
没看到我在忙吗？
Don't you see I'm busy?
那两个囚犯不见了
The two Federation prisoners, they're gone.
他们逃掉了？
You mean they've escaped?
我发誓，守卫们没有失职
I swear, no one was at fault.
一共有十个守卫，他们一直在看守
The guards, ten of them, were constantly on duty
那间牢房
watching the cell.
给他们送饭的时候
When we opened it to give them food,
却发现他们不见了，而那里没有别的出口
they simply weren't there, and there was no way out.
如果你是在对我撒谎——
If you're lying to me--
我发誓
I swear.
好吧，上尉
All right, lieutenant.
执行第四号命令
Implement special occupation order number four.
- 马上 - 遵命
- Immediately. - Sir.
你们就只会笑吗？
Is that all you can do? Smile?
- 你自由了，舰长 - 此话怎讲？为什么你们要放了我
- You are free, captain. - I wanna know how I'm free, and why.
其实我也有些问题
Indeed, there are several questions
- 想问问你们 - 为什么你们还能保持冷静
- I would like to ask as well. - This idiotic placidity of yours,
为什么你们拒绝自卫
your refusal to do anything to protect yourselves.
我们已经回答过那个问题了
We have already answered that question.
对我们来说，暴力是不可想象的
To us, violence is unthinkable.
注意
Attention.
注意，所有奥伽尼亚人，注意
Attention, all Organians. Attention.
我是柯尔指挥官
This is Commander Kor.
那两个联邦的囚犯逃跑了
The two Federation prisoners have escaped,
很显然是有外界的协助
obviously with outside aid.
我要你们马上将他们送回来
They will be returned immediately.
否则的话…
So that you will know we mean what we say...
…听好了
...listen.
那是相位枪的声音，去看看情况
Those are Klingon phasers. Take the door.
趴下，先生们
Get down, gentlemen.
刚才，已经有两百个奥伽尼亚人…
In the courtyard of my headquarters...
…在我总部的庭院里被处死了
...two hundred Organians have just been killed.
两百条性命啊
Two hundred of them.
每隔两个小时，我们会再杀200个…
In two hours, 200 more will die...
…直到那两个联邦的间谍…
...and 200 more after that...
…回到我们的手上
...until the two Federation spies are turned over to us.
这是柯尔的命令
This is the order of Kor.
- 你们听到了吗？ - 是的，舰长
- Did you hear them? - Yes, of course, captain.
但我们坚持原来的意见
But nothing has changed.
史波克…
Well, Mr. Spock...
…看来只能靠我和你了
...it seems it's up to you and me.
看来只能这样了，舰长
It would appear so, captain.
联邦在我们的训练上投资了不少钱
The Federation has invested a great deal of money in our training.
现在是时候做出回报了，我们还有2个小时
They're about due for a small return. We have two hours to do it.
但只有2个小时，还会有更多奥伽尼亚人死去——
But only two. More Organians will die--
不，史波克，不会再有人死去了
No, Mr. Spock. No more will die on account of us.
相位枪在哪里？
Where are those phasers?
我不能告诉你
I cannot tell you.
你说你很讨厌暴力
You've told us a great deal about how you hate violence.
但如果你不告诉我相位枪在哪
Unless you tell me where those phasers are,
我会让你好好尝尝暴力的滋味的
you're gonna have more violence than you know what to do with.
你是说你想动粗了？
You mean you would actually use force?
那就要看你怎么做了
It's entirely up to you.
艾尔波恩，这没关系
Ayelborne, this is of no matter.
你就告诉他吧，他…
Perhaps you'd better let him have what he wants. He...
好吧，但这对你没有好处
Very well, but it will do you no good.
枪就在那个柜子里
They're in that cabinet.
我对你们、你们的星球以及文化一点爱都没有
Gentlemen, I have no great love for you, your planet, your culture.
尽管如此，我和史波克先生还是要出去
Despite that, Mr. Spock and l are gonna go out there...
而这相当于送死
...and quite probably die.
向你们证明，有些东西是值得我们去拼死争取的
In an attempt to show you that there are some things worth dying for.
你们只有两个人对抗一支军队
There are only two of you against an army.
难道你不觉得你的行为是毫无意义的吗？
Don't you realise that what you intend to do will be hopeless?
来吧，史波克，我们走
Come on, Mr. Spock. Let's get out of here.
- 他们是勇士 - 是的，不过有勇无谋
- Brave men. - Yes, but so foolish.
但挺有意思的
Interesting, however.
我们不能就这么让他们为所欲为
Of course, we cannot allow it.
我不想阻止他们
To stop them is very bad.
但必须这么做，否则他们或许会伤到对方
It is necessary. They may harm one another.
- 特里非恩？ - 他们会等到夜幕降临再行动
- Trefayne? - They will wait until darkness.
- 然后呢？ - 暴力，野蛮，不可想象
- Then? - Terrible, inconceivable. Savage.
我们再等等
We will wait.
我们能拿下那两个守卫吗？
Mr. Spock, can we get those two guards?
你觉得我们逃出这里的机会有多大？
What would you say the odds are on our getting out of here?
说不准，舰长
Difficult to be precise, captain.
机会大概在1/7824.7左右吧
I should say approximately 7,824.7 to one.
说不准？
Difficult to be precise?
1/7824？
7,824 to one?
1/7824.7
7,824.7 to one.
那已经很准确了
That's a pretty close approximation.
- 我想尽量精确一点 - 你干得不错了
- I endeavour to be accurate. - You do quite well.
把你的相位枪调到击晕模式
Set your phaser on stun.
我们的目标是敌方首领，而不是这些小卒子
We're after the top dog, not the members of the pack.
很好
Very good.
但如果有必要的话，就开杀戒，明白吗？
But if the situation calls for it, we kill. Is that clear?
明白了，舰长
Clear, captain.
我来对付左边那个
I'll take the one on the left.
开火
Fire.
- 他们开始行动了 - 好的
- It has begun. - Very well.
- 这并不简单 - 你们准备吧
- It will be hard. - Prepare yourselves.
- 没有效果，指挥官 - 没有？
- No results, commander? - Nothing.
我不理解这些人
I cannot understand these people.
他们知道什么是死亡吧？
They know what death is, don't they?
他们似乎从不担心任何事情
They do not seem to be worried about anything.
当一名军事指挥官已经够糟糕了
Bad enough to be a military governor,
更别说要当这些小绵羊的指挥官！
but to govern a population of sheep!
好吧，上尉
Very well, lieutenant.
- 再抓200个 - 是的，指挥官
- Round up 200 more. - Yes, sir.
都是傻子！难道要我把他们全杀了？
Fools! Will I have to kill them all?
如果你不回答我的问题
If you don't tell me what I want to know,
我就会杀了你，明白吗？
I'll kill you here and now. Is that clear?
明白，明白
Yes, yes.
柯尔在那间办公室里吗？
Is Kor in his office down there?
是的
Yes.
人质呢？说，说
What about the hostages? Talk. Talk.
我现在要去再抓200个
I am to gather 200 more.
你们要杀了这些人？
To be killed?
史波克
Mr. Spock.
现在机会有多大？
Well, what are the odds now?
大于1/7000了，舰长
Less than 7,000 to one, captain.
我们能到这已经很不错了
It's remarkable we've gotten this far.
大于1/7000
Less than 7,000 to one.
我们渐入佳境了
Well, getting better, getting better.
别动，指挥官
Just stay where you are, commander.
你们能越过我的守卫来到这里很不错
You have done well to get this far through my guards.
有些守卫根本没有在
I believe you'll find that several of them
尽职看守
are no longer in perfect operating condition.
好吧
So.
你们来了
You are here.
我觉得你会想知道
You will be interested in knowing
有一条联邦星舰
that a Federation fleet is on its way here
正在赶来这里
at the moment.
而我们的舰队正在准备迎接他们
Our fleet is preparing to meet them.
将军了，长官
Checkmate, commander.
不如在你杀我之前一起等等看结果会是如何？
Shall we wait and see the results before you kill me?
除非必要，我不想杀你
I don't intend to kill you unless I have to.
感情用事，仁慈
Sentimentality, mercy.
热爱和平
The emotions of peace.
这些是你的弱点，寇克舰长
Your weakness, Captain Kirk.
克林贡帝国会赢得胜利的
The Klingon Empire shall win.
想想吧，这个宇宙未来一万年的命运
Think of it. As we sit here, in space above us,
都将在我们待在这里的这段时间
the destiny of the galaxy will be decided
被决定
for the next 10,000 years.
要喝一杯吗？
Can I offer you a drink?
我们可以预祝克林贡舰队取得胜利
We can toast the victory of the Klingon fleet.
你太天真了
You may be premature.
事情不一定会像你想象的发展
There are many possibilities.
今天我们胜利了
Today we conquer.
或许有一天我们也会被打败…
Though if someday we are defeated...
…但是胜负乃兵家常事
...well, war has its fortunes, good and bad.
你知道为什么我们这么强吗？
Do you know why we are so strong?
因为我们是一个整体
Because we are a unit.
我们的每一个人都是这个整体的一部分
Each of us is part of the greater whole.
一直被监视着
Always under surveillance.
就算是像我这样的指挥官…
Even a commander like myself...
…也一直被监视着，舰长
...always under surveillance, captain.
你看
If you will note.
掩护，史波克！
Cover, Spock!
开火，开火！
Shoot. Shoot!
- 这是怎么回事，史波克？ - 无法解释，舰长，极强的热力
- What is it, Spock? - Inexplicable, captain. Extreme heat.
不止是武器，还有身体
Not only the weapons, but the bodies as well.
很抱歉，先生们，但我们必须介入这场纷争…
We are terribly sorry to be forced to interfere, gentlemen...
…因为我们不希望看到你们互相残杀
...but we cannot permit you to harm yourselves.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
我们制止了你们的暴力
We have put a stop to your violence.
是你们干的？你们？
You are stopping this? You?
现在这个星球上所有的武器
All instruments of violence on this planet
温度都升高到了350度
now radiate a temperature of 350 degrees.
已经失效了
They are inoperative.
我的舰队
My fleet.
两支舰队上的情况也是一样
The same conditions exist on both the starfleets.
不会再有战斗了
There will be no battle.
荒谬
Ridiculous.
你可以试着联系他们，你也是，舰长
I suggest you contact them. You too, captain.
现在你们的星舰就在通讯范围内
Your ship is now within range of your communications device.
寇克呼叫进取号，回复
Kirk to Enterprise, come in.
舰长
Captain.
我不明白发生了什么事
I can't explain it.
在我们接近克林贡舰队的时候
We were just closing in on the Klingon fleet when
星舰上的设备都急速升温，无法操作了
every control on our ship became too hot to handle.
我们失去了能源
Our power is gone.
相位炮停止运作了
Our phaser banks are dead.
原地就命，苏鲁
Stand by, Sulu.
我的舰队
My fleet.
现在动弹不得
It's helpless.
你做了什么？
What have you done?
当我站在这里的时候…
As I stand here...
…我也同时站在克林贡帝国…
...I also stand upon the home planet of the Klingon Empire...
…以及星际联邦的故乡行星上
...and the home planet of your Federation, captain.
我要阻止这场疯狂的战争
I'm going to put a stop to this insane war.
- 你说什么？ - 你在说什么疯话
- You're what? - You're talking nonsense.
我正在完成我的目标
It is being done.
你不能阻止我们，谁给了你这样的权利？
You can't just stop the fleet. What gives you the right?
你不能介入
You can't interfere.
宇宙里发生的事和你无关
What happens in space is not your business.
除非双方同意立即停止敌对行为
Unless both sides agree to an immediate cessation of hostilities,
否则你们所有的武器
all your armed forces, wherever they may be,
都会马上停止运作
will be immediately immobilized.
我们有正当的理由对抗克林贡帝国
We have legitimate grievances against the Klingons.
他们侵略了我们的领地，杀害我们的人民
They've invaded our territory, killed our citizens.
他们公开侵略，还妄想侵占
They're openly aggressive. They've boasted that they'll take over
- 半个银河系 - 这有什么问题？我们更强
- half the galaxy. - And why not? We're the stronger.
你们曾试图包围我们，切断重要供给，破坏贸易
You've tried to hem us in, cut off vital supplies, strangle our trade.
是你们在挑起战争！
You've been asking for war!
是你们发出最后通牒
You're the ones who issued the ultimatum
要求撤离那些争议地区的！
to withdraw from the disputed areas!
它们的归属根本不应有争议，它们是我们的
They're not disputed. They're clearly ours.
而你们现在却想用这些花招来干涉我们
And now you step in with some kind of trick.
这不是什么花招，指挥官
It is no trick, commander.
我们只是想阻止你们的战争
We have simply put an end to your war.
你们的所有作战力量
All your military forces, wherever they are,
现在都已经瘫痪
are now completely paralysed.
我们觉得干涉他人的私事…
We find interference in other people's affairs...
…是非常令人厌恶的行为
...most disgusting.
但先生们，你们让我们别无选择
But you, gentlemen, have given us no choice.
你们应该站在我们这边
You should be the first to be on our side.
他们杀了两百个人质
Two hundred hostages killed.
没有人质被杀害，舰长
No one has been killed, captain.
无数年来，这里都没有人死去
No one has died here in uncounted thousands of years.
你在说谎
You're liars.
你们在干涉一些与你们根本无关的事情
You're meddling in things that are none of your business.
即使你们拥有某种未知的力量…
Even if you have some power that we don't understand...
…也没有权利命令我们的联邦——
...you have no right to dictate to our Federation--
或是我们的帝国
Or our Empire.
——如何处理星际关系
--how to handle their interstellar relations.
我们有权——
We have the right--
去发动战争吗，舰长？
To wage war, captain?
去杀害数以百万计的无辜民众？
To kill millions of innocent people?
去摧毁一颗星球上的所有生命？
To destroy life on a planetary scale?
你是想说这些吗？
Is that what you're defending?
没人想要战争
Well, no one wants war.
但我们有正确的渠道
But there are proper channels.
人们有权去处理自己的事务
People have a right to handle their own affairs.
我们最终会…
Eventually, we will...
你们最终会获得和平
Eventually you will have peace.
但只有在数以百万计的人牺牲之后
But only after millions of people have died.
事实上，在未来
It is true that in the future,
你们和克林贡帝国将会成为亲密的盟友
you and the Klingons will become fast friends.
- 互相合作 - 绝不
- You will work together. - Never.
你的情感太不和谐了
Your emotions are most discordant.
我们不希望显得无礼
We do not wish to seem inhospitable,
但是，先生们，请你们离开这里
but, gentlemen, you must leave.
是的，请离开我们
Yes, please leave us.
只要看到像你们这样的生物…
The mere presence of beings like yourselves...
…就会让我们非常不愉快
...is intensely painful to us.
你是什么意思，“像你们这样的生物”？
What do you mean, "beings like yourselves"?
舰长，在数百万年前…
Millions of years ago, captain...
…我们是类人型生物，就像你们一样
...we were humanoid, like yourselves.
但我们已经进化到了不再需要肉体的地步了
But we have developed beyond the need of physical bodies.
你们所看到的我们…
That of us which you see is mere appearance...
…只是你们眼中的影像
...for your sake.
舰长，这只是些花招
Captain, it's a trick.
我们能制服他们，我有一支军队
We can handle them. I have an army.
太神奇了
Fascinating.
纯粹的能量
Pure energy.
纯粹的思想
Pure thought.
全非实体
Totally incorporeal.
完全不同于我们所知道的任何生物
Not life as we know it at all.
那这颗星球呢？
But what about this planet?
田野，房屋，还有这座城堡呢？
The fields, the buildings, this citadel?
可能只是地标吧
Conventionalisations, I should say.
对奥伽尼亚人来说毫无意义
Useless to the Organians.
它们的存在，只对像我们这样的访客
Created so that visitors, such as ourselves,
有着习惯的指向性作用
could have conventional points of reference.
但这有可能吗？
But is all this possible?
我们已经亲眼目睹过了
We have seen it with our own eyes.
我认为这些奥伽尼亚人在进化程度上
I should say the Organians are as far above us
已经远远超越了我们
on the evolutionary scale as we are above the amoeba.
指挥官，我们的纠纷似乎要就此告一段落了
Well, commander, I guess that takes care of the war.
显然，这些奥伽尼亚人不打算让我们斗下去
Obviously, the Organians aren't going to let us fight.
太可惜了，舰长
A shame, captain.
原本这将充满荣耀
It would've been glorious.
轮机室呼叫舰桥
Engineering to bridge.
环境控制部
Environmental control.
扫描舰桥，三
Scan bridge, three.
工程控制部
Engineering control.
环境控制部，收到
Environmental control, affirmative.
环境控制部呼叫舰桥，所有系统运作正常
Environmental control to bridge. All systems show green.
你好像在我们离开奥伽尼亚后就一直有点沉默
You've been most restrained since we left Organia.
我觉得有点难堪
I'm embarrassed.
我曾对奥伽尼亚人阻止我们这场战争的行为感到愤怒
I was furious with the Organians for stopping a war I didn't want.
我们自认为是宇宙中最强大的生物
We think of ourselves as the most powerful beings in the universe.
但令人不安的事实却是与之相反的
It's unsettling to discover that we're wrong.
舰长，奥伽尼亚人花了数百万年的时间
Captain, it took millions of years for the Organians
去进化到如今的地步
to evolve into what they are.
即使是上帝也无法在一夜间创造所有的生命
Even the gods did not spring into being overnight.
我们没有理由感到难堪
You and I have no reason to be embarrassed.
毕竟，我们已经成功了
We did, after all, beat the odds.
哦，不，不，不，史波克，我们没有成功
Oh, no, no, no, Mr. Spock. We didn't beat the odds.
我们根本毫无机会
We didn't have a chance.
这场游戏的主宰是奥伽尼亚人
The Organians raided the game.
本集结束
-=The Last Fantasy=-
谢谢观赏
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/